CIAN RONAYNE

• E-Commerce Media Specialist •

ABOUT ME

Highly capable E-Commerce Media Specialist with over a year experience working with the world's most successful Amazon Advertising Agency. Certified in Amazon Advertising (search & DSP), my expertise has contributed to an average increase of 307% in clients' Amazon media sales this year. A proven self-starter, having embraced and thrived in new roles in both the USA & UK.

EDUCATION

National College of Ireland 2017-2020 BA. | Marketing Practice (2nd Class Honors Grade 1 result)

Killester College of Further Education 2014-2015 Diploma of Higher Education | Information Technology (Distinction)

EXPERIENCE

Flywheel Digital - Ascential plc (London, UK)

August 2020 - Present

E-Commerce Media Specialist

- Strategizing and launching advertising campaigns across both AMS & DSP on behalf of clients.
- Continuously optimizing campaigns driving towards KPIs while remaining flexible to adjustments in client's strategy.
- Developing and presenting daily/weekly/monthly reporting, analytics, and performance insights for clients highlighting recent wins, challenges and growth opportunities.
- Serving as an on-call consultant for solutions to any Amazon challenges that may arise via emails, calls, in-person meetings, and reports for clients.
- Remaining ahead of the curve with developments in the Amazon Advertising space in order to provide the best service to clients.
- Mentoring new starters and instilling best practices for Media Specialists.

Club Travel Limited (Dublin, Ireland)

October 2018 - July 2020

Digital Marketing Executive

- Maintaining & updating customer databases from 8 different travel agencies.
- Analyzing customer data, and pulling reports in order to prepare & plan for future marketing campaigns.
- Managing the websites of 8 travel agencies, updating web pages with the latest info, utilizing multiple content management systems.
- Launching, optimizing & reporting on campaigns across both Facebook ads & Google ads.
- Copywriting for SEO activity (blogs etc.) and social media activity.

Two Men And A Truck (Chicago, IL, USA)

May 2018 - August 2018

Mover

- Packing, moving and safely transporting household goods, office furniture and other heavy items.
- Providing excellent customer service throughout moves, and going the extra mile for each client.
- Completing paperwork and payment collection at the end of each move.

American Eagle Outfitters INC. (Ocean City, MD, USA)

May 2016 - August 2016

Sales Associate

- Driving store sales by providing excellent customer service, and up-selling priority products in order to meet Monthly targets.
- · Serving and assisting customers on checkouts, and closing out at end of shift.

TELEPHONE +44 7857 942677

WEBSITE

EMAIL